

PROFILE

"Application Development Analyst with 2.8+ years of work experience. I enjoy develop, design and maintain technologies that improve the way the world works. Use curiosity to solve technical problems through developing, designing and maintaining the software products or system that enable client strategies. Work in challenging and dynamic environments".

ADDRESS

Parsa Khal, saltauwa, Basti, U.P 272190

HOBBIES

Travelling Playing Cricket

MAHESH KUMAR PANDEY

Application Development Analyst

CONTACT

PHONE: 7976929675, 954907039

EMAIL: Maheshpandey9919@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Arya Institute of Engineering and technologies Jaipur, Rajasthan 2015-2019

I completed my graduation from computer science branch with 74% aggregate.

St. Xavier's High School Pared Sarkar Gonda, UP

2013-2014

I completed my 12th with 83%.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy and Services

Developer, Retail, UK, Bangalore 2019–Nov, 2021

Dashboard for real time store management | | ReactJs, NodeJs, MySql

- o Mysal for data base uses where data stored related to store.
- ReactJs to create front end website where user can monitor stock on hand on real time and create replenishment or transfer if required. It has ability of data visualization as well at the real time.
- o NodeJs used to create rest api to integrate frontend and backend
- Used docker to containerize the webapp and used Git for version control

Dashboard for visualize the failure in Retail System(RMS,RIB,SIM)

- o Created java client batch to load the file into the database server
- Used NodeJs to create Api for particular sytem to see the failure reason and timing to analyze the issue quickly.
- o ReactJs for front end web to visualize the issue.
- Used Nodejs to create microservices

Development of Chatbot for Retail Domain | Node.Js, DialogFlow

- Developed Chatbot for book transfer for store to warehouse.
- o Using Node.js for Development on Dialogflow
- o Integrated Chatbot to reactJs webapp.
- o Testing and integrating for end to end user

Development and deployment for Vodafone Retail Uk \mid \mid java,MySql, Soap Webservice

- Developed multiple java client script for sim store to warehouse transfer in retail.
- Where I used soap web service to invoke the transfer request to the ware house
- Worked on java automation testing created test suit for automation testing of soap services and other scripts..
- Worked upon CI/CD pipeline of azure for deployments where we used GIT for version control
- o Have been part of business go live and several releases.
- Worked on BI Publisher to create reports and Used ADF to link these reports to RMS Application

Accenture Solutions Private Limited

Application Development Analyst Nov.2021–Present

Development and deployment Square, INC. | | ReactJs, ROR

- o Worked on internal website enhancement that was for new joiner and updated some frontend component based on ReactJs.
- o Did enhancement on backend script that is based on ruby on rail.

ACHIEVMENTS AND CERTIFICATES

- Rajasthan Hackathon
- Ethical Hacking

SKILLS

- o **Primary Skill:** ReactJS, JavaScript, NodeJs
- o **Secondary Skills:** Java, C, C++, Sql.
- o **Frameworks:** React, Flask, Dialogflow, Express Js, and Flutter.
- o **DevOps Tools:** Docker
- o Cloud Platform: Azure Cloud platform
- o Web development: ReactJs, Html, CSS, Rest API.
- o **Database:** MySQL, PostgreSQL,MongoDb.
- o **IDEs and SDKs:** Visual Studio, Jupyter Notebook, Android Studio, eclipse.
- o Other: PowerBI, RPA, php, Ruby On Rails, Git.